{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following is the reduced form of a temporary electron carrier molecule?", "opta": "FADH2", "optb": "ATP", "optc": "NADP+", "optd": "CO2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following is a product of both cyclic and noncyclic photophosphorylation?", "opta": "NADPH", "optb": "O2", "optc": "ATP", "optd": "Carbohydrate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following represents a correct ordering of the events that occur during the respiration of glucose in the absence of O2?", "opta": "Glycolysis; citric acid cycle; oxidative phosphorylation", "optb": "Glycolysis; oxidative phosphorylation; citric acid cycle", "optc": "Oxidative phosphorylation; citric acid cycle; glycolysis", "optd": "Glycolysis; fermentation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rate of photorespiration in most plants increases at.higher temperatures. Some plants have evolved a somewhat round-about system to deal with this problem. This series of reactions is called", "opta": "ETS (electron transfer system in light reactions", "optb": "C4 pathway", "optc": "Photosystem II", "optd": "Calvin cycle", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "NADP+ is reduced to NADPH during", "opta": "light dependent reactions", "optb": "photorespiration", "optc": "calvin cylcle", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "More ATP is manufactured during __________ than at any other time in all of cellular metabolism.", "opta": "fermentation", "optb": "glycolysis", "optc": "the light reactions of photosynthesis", "optd": "oxidative phosphorylation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Electron transport systems play a vital role in", "opta": "Calvin cycle", "optb": "photorespiration", "optc": "light-dependent reactions", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Antenna complexes, electron transport chains, and carbon fixation are all found in", "opta": "animal cells", "optb": "bacterial cells", "optc": "plant cells", "optd": "association with the reactions of the citric acid cycle", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Where does the O2 come from that is essential for the proper functioning of oxidative phosphorylation?", "opta": "Fermentation", "optb": "Light reactions of photosynthesis", "optc": "Dark reactions of photosynthesis", "optd": "Carbon fixation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Carbon fixation requires the expenditure of ATP molecules which is generated by", "opta": "formation of glucose during the Calvin cycle", "optb": "replenishment of chlorophyll", "optc": "ETS (electron transfer system) during the light reactions", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A cyclic electron transport process is the characteristic of", "opta": "photosynthesis", "optb": "methane oxidation", "optc": "sulfide oxidation", "optd": "methane production", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In oxygenic photosynthesis, the electron donor is", "opta": "water", "optb": "oxygen", "optc": "NADH", "optd": "NADPH", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The followings are the products of the light reactions of photosynthesis except", "opta": "ATP", "optb": "oxygen", "optc": "NADPH", "optd": "glucose", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The vast majority of the molecules that act as energy carriers to power cellular activities are made in", "opta": "the nucleus", "optb": "the Golgi apparatus", "optc": "the cytosol", "optd": "the mitochondria and chloroplasts", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements about energy metabolism is false?", "opta": "The energy that powers living systems ultimately comes from the sun", "optb": "All animals in some way rely on plants for their energy", "optc": "Plants provide the water and CO2 that animals need to carry out respiration", "optd": "All eukaryotic organisms carry out respiration in the presence of O2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In cells having organelles, the steps of the Krebs cycle and the electron transport system occur in the", "opta": "cell membrane", "optb": "mitochondria", "optc": "endoplasmic reticulum", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As a result of the photosynthetic process, which product is formed?", "opta": "Oxygen", "optb": "Water", "optc": "Carbon dioxide", "optd": "Both (a) and (b)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A eukaryotic cell that can carry out only fermentation instead of the complete aerobic respiration of glucose", "opta": "produces less CO2", "optb": "is lacking in O2", "optc": "has mitochondria present", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the maximum absorption wavelength for photosystem I in green plants?", "opta": "550 nm", "optb": "600 nm", "optc": "700 nm", "optd": "750 nm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Carbon dioxide is reduced in", "opta": "noncyclic photophosphorylation", "optb": "the Calvin cycle", "optc": "the light reactions", "optd": "both light and dark reactions", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During the light-dependent reactions of photosynthesis, which of the following does not occur?", "opta": "Splitting of water", "optb": "Carbon dioxide fixation", "optc": "Release of oxygen", "optd": "Absorption of light energy by photosystems", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following structures or processes are logically associated with chloroplasts?", "opta": "Plant cells", "optb": "Chlorophyll", "optc": "Thylakoid membranes", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In oxygenic photosynthesis, water is split in order to provide the", "opta": "electrons needed to reduce P680", "optb": "O2 needed for the dark reactions", "optc": "electrons needed to reduce NADH", "optd": "electrons needed for cyclic photophosphorylation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Where do the protons come from that make up the proton gradient used in the light reactions of photosynthesis?", "opta": "Glucose", "optb": "ATP", "optc": "H2O", "optd": "NADPH", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Oxidative phosphorylation is to respiration as __________ is to photosynthesis", "opta": "carbon fixation", "optb": "electron transport chain", "optc": "light capture by chlorophyll", "optd": "reduction of NADPH", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following serves as a reactant in photosynthesis and a product in cellular respiration?", "opta": "O2", "optb": "CO2", "optc": "Sunlight", "optd": "ATP", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hydrogen (electron) acceptor in the light reactions is", "opta": "ADP", "optb": "NADP+", "optc": "NAD+", "optd": "FADH", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cytochrome c oxidase complex", "opta": "accepts electrons from cyt c", "optb": "donates four electrons to O2", "optc": "pumps protons out of the matrix space", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the Calvin cycle, carbon dioxide is fixed in a reaction with the", "opta": "ribulose diphosphate", "optb": "ribulose phosphate", "optc": "ribose tri phosphate", "optd": "3-phosphoglyceric acid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do NAD+, NADP+, and FAD+ all have in common?", "opta": "They are reduced", "optb": "They have a full complement of electrons", "optc": "They are oxidized", "optd": "They are what is used during carbon fixation in photosynthesis", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In noncyclic photophosphorylation, the ultimate acceptor of electrons that have been produced from the splitting of water is", "opta": "NADP+", "optb": "chlorophyll a", "optc": "carbon dioxide", "optd": "chlorophyll b", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The breakdown of glucose occurs by the process known as", "opta": "glycolysis", "optb": "fermentation", "optc": "anaerobic respiration", "optd": "Krebs cycle", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The manufacture of ATP in both photosynthesis and respiration is made possible by", "opta": "the existence of a proton gradient across specific membranes", "optb": "the action of ATP synthase", "optc": "energy from the movement of electrons", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The end products of noncyclic photophosphorylation are", "opta": "O2, ATP and NADPH", "optb": "carbon dioxide, PGAL (phosphoglyceraldehyde), and H2", "optc": "water, ADP and NADP+", "optd": "carbon dioxide, ATP and water", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In algae, photosynthesis takes place in", "opta": "choloroplasts", "optb": "cell membrane", "optc": "mitochondria", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which enzyme is involved in carbon-fixation reaction?", "opta": "NADP reductase", "optb": "Cytochrome reductase", "optc": "Ribulose bisphosphate carboxylase", "optd": "Glycerol kinase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Assume the combined processes of photosynthesis and cellular respiration, the electrons that start as part of H2O at the beginning of the light reactions end up attaching to", "opta": "O2 to make new H2O", "optb": "NADPH to make new glucose", "optc": "pyruvate to make ethanol", "optd": "electron transport carriers to make O2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the initial step of photosynthesis, sunlight energizes the electron pair of", "opta": "adenosine triphosphate (ATP)", "optb": "chlorophyll pigments", "optc": "water", "optd": "carbon dioxide", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Rubisco (RuBP Carboxylase-oxygenase enzyme), glyceraldehyde 3-phosphate, and NADPH all play a role in", "opta": "the dark reactions of photosynthesis", "optb": "the breakdown of glucose into CO2", "optc": "cellular respiration when O2 is present", "optd": "alcohol fermentation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The electrons that are released by the splitting of water during photosynthesis ultimately end up in", "opta": "ATP", "optb": "O2", "optc": "NADPH", "optd": "rubisco", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Glycolysis takes places in the __________ and produces __________ , which in the presence of oxygen then enters the __________ .", "opta": "cytosol; glucose; mitochondrion to complete fermentation", "optb": "cytosol; pyruvate; mitochondrion to complete fermentation", "optc": "cytosol; pyruvate; mitochondrion to complete cellular respiration", "optd": "mitochondrion; pyruvate; chloroplast to complete photosynthesis", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What process in cellular respiration is essentially the reverse of carbon fixation in photosynthesis?", "opta": "Glycolysis", "optb": "Citric acid cycle", "optc": "Oxidative phosphorylation", "optd": "Alcohol fermentation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do coenzyme A, CO2, oxaloacetate, and FADH2 all have in common?", "opta": "They are all components or products of the citric acid cycle", "optb": "They are part of the dark reactions of photosynthesis", "optc": "They are part of the reactions of lactic acid fermentation", "optd": "They are all elements of oxidative phosphorylation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the oxygen is labeled in CO2 and provide this CO2 to a plant, where it is expected to find this labeled oxygen after the plant had undergone photosynthesis?", "opta": "In the water used", "optb": "In the NADPH", "optc": "In the carbohydrate produced", "optd": "In the oxygen given off by the plant", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}